



## Valentin Micu

O Home: Constanta, Romania

**Email:** <u>valvic6@gmail.com</u> **\ Phone:** (+40) 723056230

**Website:** https://github.com/valvic66

**Website:** https://portfolio-new-site.vercel.app/

**Gender:** Male **Date of birth:** 03/12/1976 **Nationality:** Romanian

### **ABOUT ME**

After ending 16 years in the previous job and being very passionate about everything involving programming and THE WEB, I started the journey of becoming a professional web engineer. Since then, I'm definitely in love with it ALL:)

I am a very organized person, commited to work, a team player with great self learning abilities.

I love all kinds of sports, especially skating and hiking our beautiful mountains. Very fond of reading tech books but fiction as well. Can not resist any escape in nature.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

[ 08/2023 - Current ]

## **Senior Web Developer**

## Cognizant / Centrica UK

City: Remote

Country: Romania

- Released the AWS Chat for Centrica UK.
- Accepted to continue working for Centrica UK Digital Squad developing, improving and maintaining their main websites.
- Joined an exceptional team with enormous potential for advancement and elevating our coding and delivery standards.
- Stack: AWS Web Services, Ember.js, SCSS, JS

[12/2022 - 08/2023]

## **Senior Web Developer**

## Cognizant Softvision / Centrica UK

City: Remote

Country: Romania

- Started working for Centrica UK Company working in the field of green energy, mainly managing their website.
- Also involved in the creation of an omnichannel cloud contact center for British Gas main website using AWS web services with AWS connect.
- Accepted a challenging full stack role using AWS web services and in paralel developing the UI in React.
- Stack: Amazon Web Services, Amazon Connect, React, Typescript, styled-components

# [ 06/2022 - 12/2022 ] **Senior Web Developer**

## Cognizant Softvision / Ernst & Young

City: Remote

Country: Romania

- Started working for a consulting Company E&Y, part of the BIG4, managing their main website and internal employees web applications.

- Provided new features development, maintenance, bug fixes, demos to client and deploys to production in a fully Agile environment.
- Part of the interview team for new joiners and involved in mentoring junior and mid developers.
- Stack: React.js, Typescript, Apollo GraphQL, Material UI, Cypress

## [ 04/2022 - 06/2022 ]

## **Senior Web Engineer**

## Cognizant Softvision / Estee Lauder

City: Constanta, RO Full remote for SV

- Got promoted to Senior Web Engineer. Starting a Team Lead position.
- Continued working for Estee Lauder but part of a new team developing a Virtual Try On solution for the clients (Estee Lauder, Clinique, Mac Cosmetics).
- Stack: React.js, Typescript, Drupal, MobX

# [ 04/2020 - 04/2022 ] **Web Engineeer**

## Cognizant Softvision / Estee Lauder

City: Constanta, RO Full remote for SV

- Resumed working for Estee Lauder Beauty Company.
- Started mentoring developers.
- Got included into interview process for hiring new developers, which is awesome and challenging.
- Stack: React.js, Typescript, Drupal, MobX

## [10/2019 - 04/2020]

## **Mobile Web Engineer**

## Cognizant SoftVision / Furniture Augmented Reality

City: Constanta, RO Full remote for SV

- Worked on new project named FAR in React Native and AI (wanted to tackle for a long time mobile development)
- React native dev in charge with new development, refactoring and bug fixing.
- Direct communication with the client. Performed demos to the client.
- Stack: React Native, Redux Toolkit, Axio

# [ 01/2019 - 10/2019 ] **Web Engineer**

### Softvision / Estee Lauder

City: Bucharest, RO

- Continued working for Estee Lauder Beauty Company and their challenging E-commerce Websites.
- Got promoted as Web Engineer.
- Stack: React.js, Typescript, Drupal, MobX

# [ 02/2018 - 01/2019 ] **Web Developer**

### Softvision / Estee Lauder

City: Bucharest, RO

- Started a challenging E-commerce for Estee Lauder Beauty Company with the following stack: ReactJS and TypeScript, Storybook and Lerna as development environment, MobX for state management, styled-components and grid-styled for components CSS, Jest and React Enzyme for testing.
- Provided development and maintenance for all Estee Lauder managed sites as Clinique, Jomalone, Glamglow, Smashbox, Dr, Jart ... (plus a lot of more beauty brands).
- Created Genie, a site that fits all the brands' need with possibility to be styled differently
- Agile team, fixed production bugs, performed pushes to prod and lower environments, performed demos to the client on a weekly basis and kept direct communication with the client.

- Stack: React.js, Typescript, Drupal, MobX

# [ 09/2017 - 02/2018 ] **Web Developer**

### Freelancer

City: Remote

- Created React custom components for a web application platform designed to find jobs by recommendations. Started using Feathers REST. Implemented Redux in some of the custom components. Used Reactstrap components based on Bootstrap4 flex implementation. Used Underscore Is to change and polish data structure.
- Created React custom component for a local real estate company. Used React DnD module.
- Created different custom components for different remote clients and implementation of the component API.

to their web sites / applications.

- Started using Vue Is for a project in collaboration with Constanta Web Developers.
- Different remote React JS and Vue Js projects.
- Completed my presentation site: <a href="https://valvic66.github.io/website3/#/">https://valvic66.github.io/website3/#/</a>

## [ 03/2017 – 09/2017 ] **Full-Stack JavaScript Developer**

### Zen Code Entreprise

City: Constanta, RO

Started my own media Company.

- Created company site in React, using Redux as state management.
- Created company site back end in Node IS using Express framework and Mongo Database.
- Lots of projects for internal / external clients in Wordpress and React.

# [ 09/2016 - 03/2017 ] **Web Developer**

## **BLike Development**

City: Constanta, RO

- Designed and improved company site.
- Fully reconstructed front end and added mobile responsiveness in Bootstrap to a transportation company web application (Kirvad Tour).
- Improved my own Vanilla IS and jQuery skills.
- Created the front end in React for a harbour cargo storage company web application. Worked for the first time with Redux state management.

# [ 01/2016 - 09/2016 ] **Web Developer**

## **CERONAV** (Romanian Maritime Training Centre)

City: Constanta, RO

- Built and improved company own sites (internal and client exposed ones).
- Improved design for course programming site (the site used for clients to book the courses).
- Designed and improved Moodle testing sites for different expert trainers.

## **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

## $[\ 2018\ -\ 2023\ ]$ Online Courses and Certifications

## Cognizant Udemy Business, freeCodeCamp, Bootcamps

# [ 02/2018 – 08/2018 ] **Web Academy Training**

Cognizant Softvision / Estee Lauder

[ 2017 - 2018 ] HTML, CSS, JS, ReactJS Consolidated Training

Constanta Web Developers

 $[\,2000\,{\text{--}}\,2016\,]$  Master on comercial vessels for VShips Germany

[ 06/1995 – 06/2000 ] **Maritime Academy "Mircea cel Batran"** 

 $[\,06/1990$  –  $06/1995\,]$  Military High School "Alexandru Ioan Cuza"

### **LANGUAGE SKILLS**

Other language(s):

## **English**

LISTENING C1 READING C1 WRITING C1

**SPOKEN PRODUCTION C1 SPOKEN INTERACTION C1** 

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

## **DIGITAL SKILLS**

Agile Metodology | Git | HTML & CSS | JavaScript | React | React Native | Vue JS | Type Script | BitBucket | Ember.Js | Redux, Redux Toolkit | Axios | GltLab | MaterialUI | Prisma ORM | FastifyJS | Node js (express framework) | AWS Web Services | React/MobX

### **DRIVING LICENCE**

Motorbikes: AM Cars: R